-天啊  她的脸  -她怎么了
- God. Her face. - What happened to her?
有脉搏  她还活着
I got a pulse. She's still alive.
快拿轮床来  快
Get a gurney. Now!
哪去了
Where'd it go?
什么哪去了  亲爱的
Where'd what go, darling?
我在马戏团餐厅打包的菜  就放在这里
My leftovers from le cirque. They were right here.
冰箱这个地方现在空了
Right where this hole in the fridge is.
我本来打算用那份烤里脊牛排
I was gonna use that chateaubriand
给今早的炒蛋加料的
for my morning scramble.
肯定不是我吃的
Well, I certainly didn't eat them.
我要是把剩菜全塞肚子里
I wouldn't look this good if I was...
怎么可能保持这种身材
pigging out on leftovers.
这种事已经不是第一次发生了
Yes, well, this isn't the first time this has happened.
过去这个月  吃的东西总是失踪
Food has been going missing for the past month.
不仅是剩菜
It's not just leftovers, either.
还有花生酱  洋蓟
It was the peanut butter, uh, artichokes,
一夸脱的咖哩肉汤  没了
A whole quart of mulligatawny soup--gone.
也许你又开始梦游吃东西了
Well, maybe you've been sleep eating again.
"又开始"  我从未"梦吃"  "梦游吃"
Again? I've never sleep ated-- sleep ate--
吃东西  我有吗
Eaten-- have I?
我去上课了
Hey. I'm off to class.
你觉得那份烤里脊牛排好吃吗
How did you like that, uh, chateaubriand?
其中的白葡萄酒酱汁是不是棒极了
Wasn't that a wonderful white wine reduction?
什么烤里脊牛排
What chateaubriand?
好吧  肯定是钟点工
All right. It's the housekeeper.
我就知道  她开始变胖了
I knew it. She has been putting on weight.
抱歉  儿子  她已经三天没来了
Sorry, darling. She hasn't been here for three days.
也许地板下住着小小"借物人"
Maybe there are tiny borrowers living under the floorboards
晚上出来偷你的食物
who come out at night to steal your food.
这不现实
It's not realistic.
他们太小了  根本打不开冰箱门
They'd be too small to get the fridge door open.
不过这里肯定有问题
No, but something is going on here, though.
我会找到答案
And I'm gonna find out what.
不就是少了些吃的嘛  卡塞尔
So some food disappeared, Castle.
有什么了不起的
What's the big deal?
不会是你吧
It wasn't you, was it?
我知道你讨厌买日用品
I know you hate to go grocery shopping.
你不是吧  卡塞尔
Seriously, castle?
从周二起我就没去你家了
I haven't been to your place since Tuesday.
对
Right.
也许我的家被超级耗子入侵了
Maybe my apartment's being invaded by some kind of super rat.
无论是什么事  我已经采取了大胆的措施
Whatever's going on, I've taken bold steps
确保这种事不会再发生了
to ensure it never happens again.
两位护士看到有人
These two nurses saw some guy
在凌晨四点把人扔下就开车走了
do a dump and drive around 4:00 A.M.
急救中心尽力挽救被害人
The trauma unit tried to save our vic,
但她没有挺过去
But she didn't make it.
如果这个人是凶手  为什么送她来急诊中心
If he's our killer, why would he take her to the E.R.?
也许他良心上过不去
Maybe he had a guilty conscience.
护士有没有看清楚司机的样子
Did the nurses get a good look at the driver?
没有  但她们看到他的车
No, but they did see his car.
是辆蓝色轿车
It was a blue sedan.
医院保安正在找监控录像
Hospital security's trying to get me some footage
看能不能看清车牌
to get the license plate.
好的  在医院开始排查
Okay, set up a canvass around the hospital.
得找到看清楚司机长相的人
We need to find someone that got a good look at the driver.
被害人身份知道吗
And where's our vic?
尸体依然在急救中心
Her body's still in the trauma bay.
据说  样子很惨
Word is, she was pretty messed up.
警告下两位
Uh, let me caution you.
心脏脆弱者不易观看
This is not for the faint of heart.
这次我同意你的观点
For once, I agree with you.
伤口是什么造成的
What did this to her?
任何都有可能  从撬棍到切割刀
Could be anything from a crowbar to a box cutter.
但看起来像是爪痕
But they look like claw marks.
但我无法分辨是什么类型的
I just can't tell what kind.
如果是动物造成的  伤口应该是咬痕才对啊
If it was an animal, wouldn't there be bite marks?
我要做详细尸检  确定死因
I might not find them until I do a complete exam
才有可能会找到咬痕
to determine the exact cause of death.
现在的情况是没有犯罪现场
Given the fact that we don't have a crime scene,
有没有显示她遇害地点的线索
is there any indication of where she was attacked?
没有  但我可以告诉你遇害时间
No, but, uh, I can tell you when.
根据发炎的程度  我可以说被害人
Based on the inflammation, I'd say the victim
在死前五六个小时就已经受伤了
sustained her injuries five to six hours before she died.
我们会查明她的身份
Well, we figure out who she is,
也会查清楚她为什么惨遭毒手
We'll find out how she wound up this way.
她叫安·卡蒂诺  27岁
Her name is Anne Cardinal, 27 years old.
印第安人
She was native american.
在纽约州中部的奥内达加保留区长大
Grew up on the onondaga reservation in central new york.
有亲属吗
Any next of kin?
没有  她没有兄弟姐妹
No. She had no siblings,
双亲已经去世
And both of her parents are gone.
她住在哈德森大学的校外宿舍
She lived in off-campus housing for Hudson University,
她在那里攻读进化生物学博士学位
Where she was working toward a PhD in Evolutionary Biology.
好的  叫鉴证组去她的住处
All right. Send C.S.U. to her apartment.
问问她的朋友和邻居知不知道
Talk to friends and neighbors to see if they know of
她认识的人中有没有开蓝色轿车的
anyone in her life who drove a blue sedan.
还有谁想弄花她的脸
And who wanted to mangle her face.
对于脸部伤痕  我可能有解释
I may have an explanation for those facial wounds.
原来被害人在"安居所"养老院工作
Turns out our victim worked at a retirement home called haven house.
恶毒嗜血的老人家
Vicious, blood-thirsty old folks,
这是你的想法吗
is that your theory?
这不是人住的养老院  卡塞尔
This home is not for people, Castle.
是一家灵长类动物保护所
It's a primate sanctuary.
住的主要是从电影界退下来的
Mostly for apes and chimpanzees and monkeys
猿  黑猩猩  猴子
who have retired from the movie business.
我小时候一直想要只宠物猴子
Ah, I always wanted a pet monkey when I was a kid.
我是《好奇乔治》的超级粉丝
Big "Curious George" Fan.
等乔治长大你再看看
Yeah. Wait till George grows up.
成年黑猩猩可以长到200磅
An adult chimpanzee can reach 200 pounds,
可以撕碎成年男性的脸手及传宗接代部位
Tear off a man's face, hands, and naughty bits.
好了  我们去灵长类动物保护所
All right, we're gonna go to the primate sanctuary.
如果安是在那里遇袭的
If Anne was attacked there,
也许有人将她弃尸掩饰此事
maybe someone dumped her body to cover it up.
轿车方面有进展就打我电话
And call me if you get anything on that sedan.
乔治才不会那样做
George would never do that.
真是可怕的损失
This is a terrible loss.
安是非常优秀的学生
Uh, I mean, Anne was a-a brilliant student
人也非常好
and a lovely person.
鉴于她受的伤  我需要问清楚
Given her wounds, I need to ask,
在这里安与灵长类动物的接触达到什么程度
how much interaction did Anne have with the primates here?
很少有直接的接触
Well, very little in terms of direct contact.
但我们有严格的培训指导
Uh, but we have very strict training guidelines
对所有员工都是
for all of our employees.
我还是会叫鉴证组过来
Still, I'll need the crime scene unit
彻底调查这里
to do a thorough investigation of this facility.
没问题  我会尽全力帮忙
Of course. Anything I can do to help.
我无法想象她被动物伤害了
I can't imagine she was harmed by any of our animals.
它们从来没有对她或任何人
They've never shown any aggressive behavior
有过攻击行为
towards her or anyone else.
戴文博士  你对安·卡蒂诺有多了解
Now, Dr. Devlin, how well did you know Anne Cardinal?
在哈德逊大学  我是她的辅导员
I was her faculty advisor at Hudson University.
几个月前
And when I found out
我发现她没工作
she was taking time off a couple of months ago,
就让她到这里工作
I offered her a job here.
那她的工作是什么呢
And what sort of work did she do?
我申请了一个基金
Oh, I have a grant
研究灵长类的社会性行为
to study the social behaviors of primates.
我雇了些哈德逊的学生
And I hire Hudson students...
比如她  还有身边的这位弗兰科
Like her and Franco here
协助照顾动物
to help manage the animals' care.
他们都没有杀人的倾向吗
Uh, and none of them have homicidal impulses,
尤其是这位月光
not even Moonshine here?
尤其不会是月光
Especially not moonshine.
他从出生起就生活在人类身边
He's been around people his whole life,
而且他很合群
And he's very social.
你们俩最后一次见到安是什么时候
Uh, when was the last time either of you saw Anne?
昨天我们一起工作  她似乎一切都很好
We worked together yesterday. She seemed totally fine.
但她提前下班了  这不是她的作风
She did leave early. That wasn't like her.
她说有要紧事要做
Said she had something important to do.
她有说是什么事吗
Did she say what it was?
可能和那场争执有关吧
It might have had something to do with that argument she had.
什么争执
What argument?
午休时  我看见她在停车场
Uh, I saw her in the parking garage around lunchtime,
和一个男人说话
talking to a man.
我从没见过他
I'd never seen him before,
但他似乎非常生气
But he seemed very angry with her.
你觉得你能给素描专家描述他的样子吗
Do you think you could describe him to a sketch artist?
可以  一定没问题
Yeah, I most definitely could.
我知道凶手是谁
Well, I know who the killer is.
你看到那只猩猩看我的眼神了吗
Did you see how that gorilla looked at me?
看到了  我猜是情欲  卡塞尔
Yeah, I think it was lust, actually, Castle.
你...有种粗犷的帅气
You are... ruggedly handsome.
嗜血欲才对
Bloodlust, maybe.
不  别让月光给骗了
No, don't let Moonshine fool you.
我肯定他和他那些退役同伙
I'm betting he and his fellow "Retirees"
其实是高智慧人猿
Are actually super-intelligent apes,
谋划着占领纽约
Plotting to take over New York city.
他们会困住所有人
They're gonna round up all the people,
把我们关进疯人院
Put us in a sanctuary.
很可能  安发现了他们
Most likely, Anne got on to them...
他们就除掉了她
They took her out.
如果这些猴子真的密谋
Now if this monkey cabal
想除掉安以绝后患
really wanted to get Anne out of the picture,
那为什么要把她丢到医院去
Why did they drop her off at the hospital?
显然...是因为内心的斗争
Well, obviously... they were conflicted.
人和猿之间的情感关系  是非常复杂的
It's very complicated, the relationship between man and primate.
你没看《猿球崛起》吗
Didn't you see "Rise of the planet of the apes"?
警示预言啊
Cautionary tale.
不好意思打破了你的幻想  卡塞尔
Sorry to burst your bubble, Castle,
不过犯罪现场可没在安居所
But C.S.U. hasn't found a crime scene at haven house.
安不是在那里被袭击的
Anne wasn't attacked there.
那袭击是在哪里发生的  又是什么袭击她的呢
Well, then where was the attack, and by what?
打断一下
Hey, so, uh,
有目击者在医院一个街区外的地方
a witness saw a blue sedan take out a side mirror
看到一辆蓝色轿车撞掉一个后视镜
about a block away from our hospital
时间也符合
in our time window.
他们查到了牌照
They got a plate.
车主是艾迪·麦斯隆
Owner of the car was Eddie Maslon.
-他和安有什么关系  -不太清楚
- How is he connected to Anne? - Well, I'm not really sure,
但是说到伤人  艾迪再熟练不过了
but Eddie knows how to put the hurt on people.
他才因为两起谋杀在新新监狱坐了八年牢
He just did eight years in Sing Sing for murder two.
而且他也有办法弄伤安的脸
And he had a way to mess up Anne's face.
市里有记录  他养了只叫坏坏的斗牛犬
City records shows he had a pit bull named Badass.
一个判过刑的凶手再加一只具有攻击性的狗吗
A convicted killer with an attack dog?
很好  把他抓过来
All right. Pick him up.
没问题
Right on.
该死
Damn it.
我真以为是月光
I really liked Moonshine for this.
我从没见过她
I've never seen her before.
昨晚你把她丢到急诊室门口
You dumped her outside of the E.R. last night,
只是她那时是...
except she looked more like...
这个样子
this.
是你的狗干的吗
Your dog do that to her?
艾迪  你才出狱三个月
Eddie, you've been out of prison for three months.
如果不想回去的话  最好赶快坦白
You better start talking unless you want to go back.
行  我没碰她
Okay, look, I didn't touch her.
坏坏也是
And neither did Badass.
不论是什么东西伤的她
Whatever did that to her,
都不会是狗
that wasn't no dog.
那她怎么到你的车里去了呢
Then how'd she end up in your car?
我昨晚从酒吧出来
I was leaving a bar last night,
碰巧拐错了弯  进了一条巷子
and I happened to make a wrong turn down an alleyway.
看到她躺在那里  血肉模糊
And I saw her laying there. She was all messed up.
我不能把她丢在那里  让她等死
I couldn't just leave her there to die.
那你还变成活雷锋了啊
Oh, so you're a good samaritan now?
如果我想杀她
If I wanted to kill her,
那我何必载她去医院呢
why would I bring her to a hospital?
如果你想救她
If you wanted to save her,
那为什么把她扔到医院门口呢
why would you ditch her outside of one?
因为以我的记录  我知道我会被冤枉
Because with my record, I knew I'd get blamed,
现在不就是这样吗
which is exactly what's happening now.
是啊
Yeah.
好人没好报
No good deed, huh?
行
Okay, fine.
那你说说你在哪里找到她的
Then why don't you tell me where you supposedly found her?
这是血迹
Well, it's blood.
也许艾迪没说谎
Maybe Eddie was telling the truth.
你得看看这个
You need to see this.
我的天
What the...
脚印
Footprints.
巨大的脚印
Giant footprints...
可能是什么野兽  那些恐怖的抓痕
Made by some kind of beast. Those vicious claw marks,
残忍的伤口
savage wounds,
她的血迹
her blood,
还有这些脚印
these footprints...
这都指向一件事
It all adds up to one thing.
真凶是大脚怪
She was killed by bigfoot.
真的  贝克特
Seriously, Beckett,
你知道这意味着什么吗
Do you have any idea what this means?
我们即将成为全国
We are about to be the first people in the nation--
不  全世界  第一个侦破大脚怪谋杀案的人
no, the world-- to solve a bigfoot murder.
真有趣  卡塞尔  不过大脚怪是不存在的
Very funny, Castle, but there is no such thing as bigfoot.
这句话你跟那些
Tell that to the people
这四百年来亲眼见过它们的人说去
who've been sighting him for 400 years.
我测了血型
So I typed the blood.
和死者的一样
It's a match to our victim.
别管血迹了
Never mind the blood.
你对这个怎么看
What is your opinion on these?
以我的专业知识  我看不出
Well, professionally, I can't speculate
这是什么  卡塞尔先生
what those are, Mr. Castle.
但个人而言  我认为
But personally, I can say
任何相信大脚怪传说的都是混蛋
that anyone who believes in bigfoot is an ass.
那是无知的人常常会下的断言
That is a common assertion amongst the uninformed.
好吧  老兄  就算有大脚怪
Okay, buddy, let's say there is a bigfoot.
一个巨大长毛  酷似猩猩的怪物
How does a giant hairy ape-man
在城市里怎么会没人看到
get around the city unseen?
很简单  沿着大脚印往那边看
Easy. Follow the big fat footprints.
什么
What?
地铁隧道
Subway access tunnel.
从飓风桑迪之后  这些隧道很多都被关闭了
Since hurricane Sandy, a lot of those are still closed.
就成了大脚怪的通行场所
So bigfoot's been using them to get around.
卡塞尔  那太荒谬了
Castle, that's ridiculous.
你怎么能说
How can you say...
瞧瞧这些大脚印
Look at these footprints.
我感兴趣的是这些正常人的脚印
These are the footprints that I'm interested in.
它们位于尸体附近
They're near where the body was.
鉴证组说这些是在过去的24小时内留下的
C.S.U. Said that they were made within the last 24 hours.
那可能是艾迪·麦斯隆的
Could be Eddie Maslon's?
这是13码的鞋
At size 13?
那家伙那么矮  不可能有这么大的脚
The guy's too short to have feet this big. No.
这些脚印才是我们目前最好的线索
These boot prints are our best lead.
是这些脚印
These prints,
而不是那些巨大的脚印
not the tracks from the giant clown feet.
是啊  我们到了犯罪现场  却要忽视证据
Yes, let's go to a crime scene and ignore the evidence.
你是说有人嫁祸给大脚怪吗
You're saying someone framed bigfoot?
卡塞尔  我是说  有人
All I'm saying, Castle, is that someone--
一个人类
A human being--
在那条巷子里留下了大脚怪的脚印
left the bigfoot prints in that alleyway.
是啊  然后伪造现场
Yeah, and staged the crime scene
使之看起来像大脚怪是凶手
to make it look as though bigfoot was the killer?
为什么要大费周章把罪责引向大脚怪
Why go through the trouble of blaming bigfoot,
那种生物甚至很少有人相信其真的存在
a creature a select few of us even believe exists,
更别说成为谋杀案的嫌疑人了
never mind could be a murder suspect?
说到嫌疑人
Speaking of suspects,
安的老板帮着把那家伙的素描像画出来了
Anne's boss came through with a sketch of the guy
也就是她死那天和她发生争吵的人
she argued with the day she died.
好好看看  卡塞尔
Take a look, Castle.
一个嫌疑人  请注意重点在这个"人"上
A person of interest, emphasis on the word "Person."
去找安的家人和朋友谈谈
Talk to Anne's friends and family
看看有没有人能认出他
and see if anyone recognizes him.
我觉得现在还不能排除大脚怪作案的嫌疑
I wouldn't rule out bigfoot just yet.
调查发现  在过去的几个月中
Turns out there have been dozens of reported bigfoot sightings
城里出现了几十起声称发现大脚怪的报告
in the city in the past couple of months.
是吗
Is that right?
莱恩警探  快告诉我们
Why, Detective Ryan, please tell us
这一最新而又令人兴奋的进展
about this new and extraordinary development.
比如这位住在布鲁克林的女士
Like this woman in brooklyn.
她声称大脚怪试图爬进
She says that bigfoot tried to break into her apartment
-她位于二楼的家里  -先生们
- On the second floor. - Gentlemen.
我这人不喜欢打击你们的信心
I hate to rain on your parade.
-是吗  -不是
-Do you? - No.
但关于大脚怪的报道
But here's the reason
突然暴增的原因是这个
that bigfoot reports have spiked.
两个月前
Two months ago,
一档叫《怪物任务》的电视节目
The TV show "Mission: monster,"
悬赏100万美元
put out a $1 million reward
给捕获或能证明大脚怪存在的证据
for the capture and/or proof that bigfoot exists.
瞧见没  卡塞尔  所有这些
See, Castle? All of this evidence
你声称大脚怪存在的证据
that you claim proves bigfoot's existence
不过是人们为了钱蓄意制造的
is actually people angling for money.
所以你是说这一切只是个巧合吗
So you're saying it's just a coincidence
安的工作是和灵长类动物打交道
that Anne was working with primates
其神秘被害的地点附近又发现了大脚怪的脚印
and mysteriously killed where bigfoot prints were found?
不  不是巧合  只是恶作剧罢了
No, not a coincidence. Just a hoax.
如果真是恶作剧
If it's such a hoax,
那你告诉我为什么我发现了这个
then tell me why I found this.
我调出了她的通话记录
I dug into her phone records.
结果发现  她死前的最后一通电话是
Turns out, the last phone call she ever made
打给达雷尔·米克斯的
was to Darrell Meeks.
那位达雷尔·米克斯吗
The Darrell Meeks?
谁是达雷尔·米克斯
Who's Darrell Meeks?
竟然问谁是达雷尔·米克斯
他是一个世界闻名的神秘动物学家
Just a world-renowned cryptozoologist.
那可是个科学家的一种
That's a scientist
专门致力于搜寻尚未被发现的生物
who searches for as-yet undiscovered creatures.
就比如独角兽和半人马吗
Such as unicorns and centaurs?
女妖和小妖吗
Banshees and leprechauns?
米克斯博士恰巧是
Doctor Meeks also happens to be
研究大脚怪最权威的专家
the foremost authority on bigfoot.
你瞧  她死的那天还给他打电话了
And lo and behold, she called him on the very day she died.
你还是认为大脚怪与此案无关吗
Still think bigfoot has nothing to do with this?
帕穆特那边有所发现
Perlmutter's got something for us.
你们两个过去看看
Why don't you guys head over there?
卡塞尔和我去找
Castle and I will talk to
全世界关于大脚怪最权威的专家谈谈
the world's foremost authority on bigfoot.
竟然是副手
The "B" Team.
-你不也是替班的吗  -就是啊
- Talk about the "B" Team. - Yeah.
我只是想看到卡塞尔沮丧的表情
Look, I had hoped to see castle's look of dismay
因为我会告诉他死因
when I told him cause of death
不过是颅骨受到钝力重击
was nothing more exotic than blunt-force trauma to the cranium.
似乎她的头部被球棒
It--it seems that she was clobbered over the head
或管子猛敲过
with a club or a pipe.
你可以在电话里告诉我们的
You coulda said so over the phone.
但我还有另外两个很重要的发现
Ah, but I also made two highly intriguing discoveries.
关于她脸上的那些伤口吗
About the wounds on her face?
那些伤口的成因尚无法确定
Uh, well, their cause is still undetermined,
但更有趣的地方在于
But of far greater interest is the fact--
因为那些很可能是爪子撕裂的
'cause they could be claw marks.
大脚怪是有脚爪的
Bigfoot has claws.
金刚狼也有  那是真实存在的吗
So does wolverine. Is he real?
你们俩闹完没
Are you done?
我在她的头部伤口里发现了这块碎玻璃
I found this glass embedded in her head wound.
那上面有一层增透膜
It has an antireflective coating,
就像镜片上常用的那种
like on prescription lenses.
但她并不戴眼镜  那是从哪儿来的
But she didn't wear glasses. So where'd it come from?
我只能告诉你们那东西是被
All I can tell you is that it was practically
击中她的东西硬敲进她的颅骨中去的
hammered into her skull by whatever hit her.
我们这就送去实验室化验
We'll send it in for analysis.
好吧  你们该把这个也拿过去
Yeah, well, you should take this while you're at it.
这是在她胃里发现的
Found that in her stomach.
一个吊坠  在她的胃里
A pendant... in her stomach?
她在死前5到6小时吞下去的
It appears she swallowed it five to six hours before she died.
就是她遭受袭击的时候
The same time she was attacked.
她为什么要吞下呢
Why would she swallow it?
或许她知道自己就要死了
Maybe she knew she was gonna die
她想传达某种信息
And she was trying to send a message.
或者她不希望这个吊坠被凶手拿去
Or she was trying to keep this pendant from her killer.
这张照片是你拍的吗
Did you take this photo?
是的  当时我正在加拿大西部探险
Yes. Uh, it's an expedition I led in western Canada.
那是我23年来最接近它们的一次
It's the closest I've ever gotten to him in 23 years.
米克斯博士
Dr. Meeks,
安死前最后一通电话就是打给你的
You were the last person that Anne spoke with just before she died.
她打给你是为什么事
Why did she call you?
是的  我觉得她打来是想问
Yes, I-I think she called me to ask me
我是否认为大脚怪会冒险进入市区
if I thought that bigfoot would venture into an urban area.
你是怎么回答她的
And what did you tell her?
根据城市发展
Well, given development
对野生环境的侵占来说
and urban encroachment in the wilderness,
这是迟早的事
sooner or later, it was inevitable.
我怀疑她手里有
And I suspect that she had evidence
大脚怪在城市中出现过的证据
of the presence of bigfoot here in the city.
我不明白为什么她要跟你说这些事
I don't understand why she would talk to you about something like that.
安学的是进化生物学
Well, Anne was studying evolutionary biology.
她在大学是优秀学生
She was an honor student at the university,
但她实际上是位很有声望的大脚怪专家
but she was actually a hugely respected bigfoot expert.
她甚至给了我一支极为罕见的雪人的手指
She even gave me that extremely rare yeti finger.
你是说安是个大脚怪猎人吗
Are you saying Anne was a bigfoot hunter?
不  不是
N-n-no, no.
她不是猎人
No, uh, no, not a--not a hunter.
安是美国原住民
No, uh, Anne was, uh, native American.
在他们的部落文化中
And, uh, in her tribe's culture,
大脚怪被认为是善良的保护神
a bigfoot was considered... benevolent or a protector.
在她小时候  她亲眼见过一只大脚怪
When she was a child, she actually saw a bigfoot,
于是后来  她一生都致力于对他们的研究
and so after that, she devoted her life to their study.
抱歉
Excuse me.
大脚怪
So are bigfoots--
是残暴而且具有攻击性的吗
or bigfeet-- uh, violent or aggressive?
它们当然可以这样
Well, they certainly can be.
她受了怎样的伤
What were the nature of her injuries?
我是说  她是被大脚怪攻击的吗
Well, I mean, was she attacked by a bigfoot?
-不可能  -是的
- Not a chance. - Yes.
以科学的名义
Well, in the name of science,
你们能让我检查一下她死去的地方吗
would you allow me to examine where she died?
不行  就你所知
No. Now as far as you're aware,
她和除了大脚怪以外的哪个人有问题吗
did she have issues with anyone other than bigfoot?
她一直被高度监视着
Well, she was under a very high level of scrutiny.
谁在监视她
Scrutiny from whom?
某个悬赏一百万美元的电视节目
Oh, some TV show offered a $1-million reward,
许多白痴为了奖金
which unleashed a tide of idiots,
都在寻找大脚怪
all searching for bigfoot.
是的
Yes, and, uh,
这是我妻子嘉兰  她不相信大脚怪
this is my wife Garland. Uh, she's the skeptical one.
我能理解你的心情  很荣幸见到你
Trust me. I feel your pain. Pleasure.
不管怎样  我认为当人们发现
In either case, I think when people found out
安在这方面是专家时  他们就想跟着她
Anne's area of expertise, they wanted to follow her
看她是否能带他们找到真正的大脚怪
to see if she would actually take them to a real bigfoot.
要知道  安死的那天
You know, the day that she died,
有人看到她在和这个人争吵
Anne was seen arguing with this man.
你认识这个人吗
Do you recognize him?
当然  太认识了
Oh, yes. All too well.
这个人是大脚怪最大的敌人
This man is the bigfoot community's worst enemy.
他的名字叫蔡斯·迪金斯
His name is Chase Diggins,
他是个澳大利亚探险家
and he's an Australian adventurer
也是一个赏金猎人
and big game hunter.
有点像鳄鱼邓迪  印第安纳·琼斯
Kind of Crocodile Dundee meets Indiana Jones
和泰德·纽金特的混合体
meets Ted Nugent.
据米克斯夫妇称
Now according to the Meekses,
他是个暴力又极其易怒的人
he's violent and highly unstable.
而且这家伙拼命想捕获一只大脚怪
What's more is that this guy is hell-bent on bagging a bigfoot.
YouTube上有一段
I found him on YouTube
他夸口说要弄一只挂在自家墙上的视频
bragging about how he's gonna mount one on his wall.
除了和一个虚构的猿人有关的推测
Do we have anything other than speculation
我们还有别的东西
on a mythical ape-man
能把这个人和谋杀案联系起来吗
that will connect him to the murder?
我们有这个
We have this.
迪金斯有一支钩状的假肢
Diggins has a prosthetic hook for a hand?
据说他因为大脚怪的攻击而失去了胳膊
Says he lost it in a bigfoot attack
而且他几乎
And that he almost took--
不管发生了什么
However it happened,
可能就是这支钩子造成了安脸上的伤
That hook could've been what did a number on Anne's face.
他现在在哪里
Where's Chase Diggins now?
这家伙是个国际探险家
This guy is an international adventurer.
他这是在搞什么鬼
What the hell is he doing?
租这么破烂的工业废墟住
Renting an industrial crap hole like this?
为什么不住旅馆
Why not a hotel?
这家伙是大脚怪猎人
The guy hunts bigfoot.
我觉得他的行为跟理性
I don't think that rational behavior
没有一点儿关系
is something he's familiar with.
你听见了吗
You hear that?
听见了
Yeah.
兄弟  这下面有东西
Dude, there's something down there.
蔡斯·迪金斯
Chase Diggins!
纽约警察局
NYPD!
如果你在这儿  你现在最好
If you're down here, you better identify yourself
赶紧出现
right now!
兄弟
Dude...
我有一种不祥的预感  伙计
I got a bad feeling about this thing, man.
我觉得我们不应该
I-I don't think that we should--
你们是在找我吗
You gents looking for me?
安真是太可惜了
A bloody shame about Anne.
她是个很棒的大脚怪追踪者
She was one hell of a tracker.
事实上  她是我来这座城市的唯一原因
Actually, the only reason I came to the city.
传言说她知道一只真正大脚怪的下落
Word was, she knew the whereabouts of an actual squatch,
我想也许她可以带我找到他
and I figured, she might lead me to him.
你来纽约
You came to new york
追捕大脚怪
to hunt bigfoot?
看到这个了吗  警探
You see this, detective?
2008年在尼泊尔
Nepal, 2008,
在喜马拉雅山脉的岩石峭壁中
in the rocky crags of the Himalayas...
一只大脚怪不知从哪冒出来
A squatch came out of nowhere
直接扯掉了我的胳膊
and ripped my arm clean off.
所以为了报仇我会一直追捕这些混蛋
So I will hunt down every last one of those bastards
直到它们被消灭
until I have my payback.
大脚怪长什么样
What did it look like?
重达五百磅长着毛的死神  伙计
500 pounds of fur and death, mate.
它的眼睛就像疯狗一样
Eyes like a rabid dog,
但它很聪明  你知道吗
but smart, you know?
无论如何  他们说她找到了一只
Anyway, they say that she found one.
人尽皆知  但安什么都不肯说
Everyone knew it, but Anne wasn't talking.
这就是你去见她的原因吗
Is that why you went to see her?
谁告诉你的
Who told you that?
目击证人看到你和安昨天在她的
Witnesses saw you and anne arguing
工作地点外面争吵
outside of her work yesterday.
那只不过是同事之间的礼貌对话而已
Merely a polite conversation between colleagues.
真的吗
Really?
因为那晚的晚些时候  她就死了
'cause later that night, she turned up dead.
你找错人了  警探
You're squattin' in the wrong bush, detective.
我昨晚和同伴们一起去了靶场
I was at a target range last night with my mates,
不想生了手
keeping my edge sharp.
你可以去查一下
You can check it out.
这就有趣了  因为我们在那条巷子里
That's funny, 'cause we found a boot print in alleyway
安的血泊附近发现了和你穿的靴子
near a pool of anne's blood with the same tread
花纹一样的靴子印
As the boots you're wearing now.
好吧  我确实去过那条巷子
All right, look, I was in that alley,
但不是昨晚  我是前天晚上去的
but not last night, it was the night before.
你去那里做什么
What were you doing there?
我想既然她在跟踪大脚怪
Well, I figured she was tracking the beast,
那我就跟踪她
so I tracked her.
我跟踪她去了小巷
I followed her to the alley, and...
正好把这个小妖精逮了个正着
That's when I caught the wily bitch in the act.
她在干什么
The act of what?
在地上印假大脚印
Stamping fake Squatch prints in the ground is what,
用的是大脚鞋模
using molds of giant feet.
她在伪造证据
She was faking the damn evidence.
等等  等等
Now, whoa. Okay, hang--
安是个有威望的研究员
Anne was a respected researcher.
何必伪造大脚怪的证据呢
Why would she fake evidence of bigfoot?
因为我认为她找到了真家伙
Because I reckon she found the real thing,
她试图糊弄我们其他人
and she was trying to throw the rest of us off the scent.
可我看穿了她  于是去她单位找她对质
But I was on to her, so I confronted her at work.
我让她尽管提要求  她让我滚开
Offered her anything she wanted, but she told me to bugger off.
知道我怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
是你伪造了现场
You faked that site.
因为你扭曲的认为
Because somewhere in your twisted mind,
大脚怪的专家会被一只大脚怪害死
it makes sense that the expert on bigfoot would be killed by one.
我就知道
I knew it.
她找到了
She found him.
这个小贱人找到了我的大脚怪
The little bitch found my bigfoot.
听着  他不是疯了  就是在撒谎
Look, he's either crazy or he's lying.
我觉得他是疯了
I'd go with crazy,
因为看来他没说谎
'cause it looks like he's telling the truth.
他的假肢钩测试没发现安的DNA
Tests on his prosthetic hook show no trace of Anne's D.N.A.
而且他的不在场证明没问题  所以不是他
And his alibi checks out. So it's not him.
看来这位仁兄
Well, it looks like we're back to this guy
又成了我们的头号疑犯
as our number one suspect.
卡塞尔  能劳烦你取下来吗
Castle, could you please take that down?
好
You got it.
化验室鉴定出
The lab also was able to identify
我们在死者头部伤口上找到的玻璃屑
the glass shards we found in our victim's head wound.
是摄像机镜头上的
It's from a camera lens.
犯罪现场没有摄像机
There was no camera at the crime scene.
或许是凶手拿走了
Maybe our killer took it.
难怪大脚怪的图片那么少
Which would explain why there are so few photos of bigfoot.
我是指人类杀手
I meant our human killer.
对
Right.
我们重新排查一下那条小巷
Let's re-canvass near that alleyway,
看能否找到那台摄像机
see if we can find that camera.
我调查了安吞下的那个坠子
So I looked into the pendant that Anne swallowed,
发现了可疑处
and I found something strange.
什么
What?
我和她的朋友和邻里聊过
I talked to her friends and neighbors.
坠子不是安的  是贾丝婷·伯顿的
The pendant wasn't Anne's. It belonged to Justine Bolton,
是安去年就读休斯顿大学时的室友
Anne's roommate at Hudson University last year.
她知道安怎么会有这个吊坠吗
Does the roommate have any idea what Anne was doing with it?
我想问她来着  只是有个问题
Uh, I'd love to ask her, there's only one problem.
贾丝婷一年前被杀了
Justine was murdered a year ago.
而一年后
And a year later,
她的坠子在她遇害的朋友的胃里被发现
her pendant is found in her murdered friend's stomach?
不会是巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
贾丝婷的谋杀案是怎么回事
What do we know about Justine's murder?
我安排要了她的卷宗
Well, I ordered up her case files.
明天上午应该能到
They should be here by the morning.
卡塞尔  我不管你做了多少研究
Look, Castle, i don't care how much research you do,
你都无法让我相信有大脚怪的存在
you're not gonna convince me that there's a bigfoot.
我只是追查证据
I just follow the evidence
和超级大脚印
and the insanely large footprints.
有你不信的事物吗
Is there anything that you don't believe in?
当然有了  比如...
Sure, there is. There's, um...
好吧  那你呢
Okay, well, what about you?
如果你不信大脚  僵尸和鬼魂
If not bigfoot or zombies or ghosts,
那你信什么
what do you believe in?
我相信生活中不可思议的点滴
I just--I believe in the everyday magic of life.
我能看得见摸得着的东西
I mean, things that I can see and touch,
比如
Like, um,
二月从雪地里萌发出来的绿芽
the green shoots that pop through the snow in February,
熨斗大厦  还有...
or the flatiron building, or...
我听科特恩的歌时候的感觉  真是...
The way that I feel when I hear Coltrane. It's...
我也欣赏日常生活
Now I can appreciate the everyday,
为什么不能承认可能性呢
but why not live in the possible?
这个世界不像以前那么神秘了
The world just doesn't have as many mysteries anymore.
没有新大陆可以探索
There's no new continents to explore.
没有最深最黑暗的非洲去发现
There's no more deepest, darkest Africa.
所有这些都被卫星和定位仪在地图上标了出来
Everything's all mapped out by satellites and sonar,
不过  人们还在探索未知
yet, still, people reach for the unknown.
这让我们成长
It's what makes us grow.
要不是安托万·萨克斯富于想象
Coltrane wouldn't have had that saxophone
科特恩也不会有萨卡斯
if Antoine Sax hadn't imagined it.
那不是我们与
Isn't that what separates us from, uh,
动物的分别吗
say Moonshine?
有一个
Well, you know, there is one...
无法解释的
Inexplicable...
神秘现象我还坚信着
Mysterious phenomenon that I do believe in still.
我们
Us.
什么声音
What was that?
有东西触发了我的陷阱
Something set off my trap.
你设了陷阱
You set a trap?
-抓住你了  超级大鼠  -什么
- I've got you now, you super rats. - What?
没人可以偷我的东西
No one steals from me.
阿丽克西斯
Alexis?
你在干什么
What are you doing here? Mm!
她还是不接我的电话
Yeah, she's still not taking my calls.
这能怪她吗  卡塞尔
Well, can you blame her, Castle?
你把她弄成了蓝精灵
You practically turned her into a smurf.
纳美人更符合现代表述[《阿凡达》]
Na'vi would be a more contemporary reference.
不  重点是  她骗了我
No, the point is, she lied to me.
她正视着我的眼睛
She looked me right in the eye
说是别人的错
and she blamed the borrowers.
我相信她有理由
I'm sure she had a good reason.
什么理由  没吃的吗
For what, not having food?
我给了她很多零花钱
I mean, I give her a sizeable allowance.
如果不够的话  她随时可以问我要
And if that's not enough, she can always ask for more.
我说了  卡塞尔
Like I said, Castle,
每天都充满了神秘
there are plenty of mysteries in the everyday.
莱恩
Hey, Ryan,
贾丝婷·伯顿的卷宗来了吗
Has Justine Bolton's murder file come in yet?
她在和安·卡蒂诺同住的公寓
She was attacked in the apartment
遭到了攻击
that she shared with Anne Cardinal.
她窒息的方式和伤痕
The way she was choked and bruised,
像是冲动犯罪
looked like it was a crime of passion.
有嫌疑人吗
Do they have a suspect?
可惜逃了
Unfortunately, he fled,
而且案发之后再没别人看到
and he hasn't been seen since the murder.
他会不会留着蓬松长发  人高马大吗
Any chance he had long, shaggy hair and he was 8 feet tall?
不是  很遗憾  卡塞尔
Uh, no. Sorry, Castle.
是贾丝婷的男友  科特·威尔森
It was Justine's boyfriend-- Kurt Wilson.
他据称是发现尸体的人
He was the one that supposedly found the body.
他是个橄榄球运动员
He was a football player
场内场外都有伤人的前科
with a history of assaults on and off the field.
贾丝婷似乎想要摆脱他
It looked like Justine was trying to get away from him.
她遇害那天  她找了系主任
The day that she was murdered, she contacted the dean
说她打算退学
and told him that she was dropping out of school
尽管她在班上名列前茅
even though she was top of her class.
等到警察发现
By the time the cops realized
所有线索都指向科特·威尔森时  他失踪了
that all roads led to Kurt Wilson, he disappeared.
安怎么发现的
How does Anne figure into this?
作为她的室友
Well, as her roommate,
安对贾丝婷的死感到非常难过
it looks like Anne took Justine's death pretty hard.
我跟案子的负责人谈话时  他告诉我
When I spoke to the lead detective, he told me
她几个月前曾找过他
she came to him a few months back
想要看贾丝婷案的档案
and asked to see Justine's case file.
他拒绝了她  因为那是没破的凶案
He refused since it's a pending murder case,
但这说明了
But still, it means--
安在查贾丝婷的案子
Anne was looking into Justine's murder.
几个月前  那正是安退学的时候
And a few months ago--that's when Anne took time off school.
这么说  安可能不是在找大脚怪
So then maybe Anne wasn't tracking down bigfoot.
她是在找科特·威尔森
She was looking for Kurt Wilson.
搞不好她找到他了
Maybe she found him.
排查没有找到安的相机
Canvass didn't turn up Anne's camera,
但实验室的人发现了镜头上的序列号
but the lab came back with a serial number on that lens.
是某一型号的摄像机专用的——
Now it was made for a specific model--
无线网络摄像机
A Wi-Fi-enable camcorder
它可以实现云同步
that's designed to synch up to a cloud account.
我查了  安在云服务器里有个账号
I checked. Anne has a cloud account.
能打开看看吗
Can we access it?
测试  一  二  三
Testing, one, two, three.
好嘞
Okay, good.
你看时间记录
Look at the time stamp.
半夜12:20  她死的那晚
12:20 a.m. The night she died.
-天呐  天呐  -是啊  不过她不在巷子里
- Oh, my god. Oh, my god. - Yeah, but she's not in an alley.
-她这是在哪儿啊  -有人追我  有人追我
- Where the hell is she? - He's after me. He's after me.
求你  不
Oh, please! No!
看来凶案发生在树林里  而不是巷子里
So the attack took place in the woods, not that alley.
但我们得找到这树林在哪儿
But what we need to find out is where these woods are.
技术科的人正在分析相机的定位信息
Tech is trying to get the geodata off that footage
看看能不能找出确切的位置
to see if we can pinpoint the exact coordinates.
但如果她是在林子里被害的
But if she was attacked in the woods somewhere,
为何要把她扔进巷子
why move her to an alley?
因为凶手想要混淆视听
Because the killer was trying to throw us off his trail.
如果安是在找科特·威尔森
If Anne was looking for Kurt Wilson,
那他最不想要的
then the last thing he would want to do
就是把她的尸体留在
is leave her body near the same spot
自己的藏身之处
where he was hiding out.
除非她是在林子里找别的东西
Unless she was looking for someone else in those woods.
浑身长毛的东西
Something with fur?
来看看视频里的凶手长什么样子
What do we really see of our killer in this video?
他黑不溜秋  若隐若现
He's dark, looming,
孔武有力  拿着原始的武器
powerful, holding a primitive weapon.
卡塞尔  那是个人
Castle, that is a person.
我看到的是一个笨拙人形生物的影子
All I see is the silhouette of a hulking, humanoid form.
如果达雷尔·米克斯和那个独臂澳洲人是对的
If Darrell Meeks and that one-armed Aussie were right
安的确知道大脚怪在哪儿的话
and Anne did know where bigfoot was,
那视频里的可能就是他
Well, that could be him on that video.
然后呢  大脚怪背着她的尸体离开森林
Then what, bigfoot carried her body into the city on foot
徒步走进城里
from wherever these woods are
把她扔进巷子里吗
and left her in that alleyway?
这可是你自己说的
Well, you said yourself,
既然科特·威尔森不想把安的尸体
Kurt Wilson wouldn't want to leave Anne's body
留在自己的藏身之地
where he'd been hiding out.
大脚怪也不想啊
Why would bigfoot?
好  你们把威尔森的照片
Okay. Why don't you guys circulate Wilson's photo
给安的家人和朋友看看
to Anne's family and friends
问问他们最近有没见过他
and see if anyone has seen him around?
我和卡塞尔去找技术科的人
Castle and I will talk to tech
看看能不能找到这树林在哪儿
to see if we can figure out where these woods are.
说不准  可能见过吧
I don't know. Maybe.
要是再邋遢点儿
If you rough him up a little, he could be
有点儿像我在停车场见过的一个流浪汉
that homeless guy I saw hanging out in the parking garage.
什么时候见到的
When was that?
上个星期
Last week sometime.
他当时在干嘛
What was he doing?
没干嘛
Nothing, man.
看起来是在等什么
He just looked like he was waiting.
我们想要
Well, we're gonna need, uh,
停车场的监控录像
security cam footage of the garage.
那是安保公司负责的  我把他们的电话给你
It's run by a separate company. I'll get you their number.
如果威尔森知道安在追查他
If Wilson knew that Anne was after him,
他可能会跟踪她  准备杀掉她
he might have been following her, preparing to kill her.
我去安排警员排查
I'll set up a canvass
把那个区域的交通监控录像都找来
and pull traffic cam footage from that area.
说不定能发现
Maybe we can get a hit on
他在离开停车场后去了哪儿
where he went after he left that garage.
测试  一  二  三
Testing, one, two, three.
好嘞
Okay, good.
她一开始拍摄
The camera began synching to her account
摄像机就开始传输数据了
right when she started filming.
我们没找到定位信息
We couldn't pull any geodata,
但数据同步是通过手机完成的
but the synch was routed through her cell phone.
是经这个手机信号站传送的
It pinged off this cell tower here.
信号站附近有森林吗
Are there any woods near that tower?
有  是片一万英亩的自然保护区
Yes, in a 10,000-acre nature preserve...
叫布兰奇森林
called Branch Cross.
那是大脚怪的理想栖息地
That's a perfect hangout for bigfoot.
或者逃犯的
Or the fugitive.
有没有办法缩小
Now is there any way to narrow down
她拍摄视频的可能位置呢
where she was when this was being filmed?
缩不到理想的范围
Not as much as I'd like,
根据林业部门的说法
but checked with the forest service,
视频中的树木品种
the species of tree in the video...
大都生长在这片六平方英里的区域
grow mostly in this 6-square-mile area.
同时我们分析了月亮的方位
Also, between the moon's position in the sky
以及阴影的朝向
and the orientation of the shadows,
我可以告诉你  她是朝着
I can tell you that she was moving
东南方行走的
in a southeasterly direction.
她真厉害
Wow. She's good.
能调大视频的音量吗
Could you turn up the volume on the video?
-你们听得到背景声音吗  -天呐  天呐
- Do you guys hear that in the background? - Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
有人追我  有人追我
He's after me. He's after me.
能把它分离出来吗
Do you think you can isolate that?
像是水声
That sounds like water.
附近有河流和泉水吗
Are there any streams or rivers nearby?
这儿有
Right there.
她肯定是在小溪附近
She must have been near that creek,
这样范围缩小到两平方英里了
which gets us down to a 2-square-mile area.
好消息是  我们找到罪案现场了
Well, the good news is, we have our crime scene.
坏消息是
The bad news is,
它在一片深山老林里
it's in 2 square miles of remote wilderness
连路都没有
with no access by road.
你喜欢徒步野游吗
You up for a hike?
我可是徒步好手
Oh, I'm well equipped for a hike.
你这是干嘛
What are you doing?
敲敲木头喊个嗓子
Knocking on wood and vocalizing.
大脚怪就是这么远距离交流的
It's how bigfoot communicates over long distances.
真正的大脚怪猎人也这么引它们出来
And how the real bigfoot hunters lure him out.
真正的警察可不这么干
Yeah, well, the real police don't do it
以防打草惊蛇
so that our human fugitive won't know that we're coming.
相信我
Oh, trust me.
如果科特·威尔森在这地方藏了一年
If Kurt Wilson has been hiding out here for a year,
我们就找不到他了
we are not gonna find him.
我们快到了
Okay, we're close.
GPS显示这就是袭击的大概方位
GPS is showing that this is the general area of the attack.
我们只需要找到一些标志地点就可以
We just need to find some landmarks.
发生地点就在枯树边上
It happened by this downed tree,
我们找到了树
So all we gotta do is find the tree,
也就找到了犯罪现场
and we've found our crime scene.
卡塞尔  求你了  别学武基人叫了
Castle, Castle, please. No more wookiee calls.
才不是武基呢  我没学武基
It's not wookiee. I'm not doing wookiee.
我不会武基  但我闺女学得很可爱
I can't do wookiee. Alexis does a really cute wookiee.
无论你在做什么  能不能消停会儿
Well, whatever you're doing, could you stop?
你是怕它会有效
You scared it might work?
才不  我是怕我会杀了你
No, I am scared that I might murder you,
这样一来我就得处理两起谋杀案了
and then I'll have two crime scenes on my hands.
你知道  许多备受尊敬的人
You know, a lot of highly respected individuals
都相信大脚怪
believe in bigfoot.
泰迪·罗斯福在日记里就写了它
Teddy Roosevelt wrote about him in his journals.
简·古道尔就公开表明
Jane Goodall has gone on record
她对其存在可能持开放态度
saying that she's open to the possibility.
此刻
And right now, as we speak,
牛津大学的教授
Professors at Oxford
就在研究大脚怪的DNA样本
are studying bigfoot D.N.A. samples.
它们的存在是可能的
No, it is possible.
你只需要保持开放的态度
You just have to be open to it...
因为任何时候
because at any moment,
生活都会给你惊喜
life can surprise you.
伤了我的老腿了
Oh, that's not good for my knee.
你还好吗
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
我们在哪里呢
Where are we?
某种陷阱里
Some kind of trap.
我们得逃出去
Which we've gotta get out of.
卡塞尔
Castle...
你背心有什么用得上的东西吗
Do you have anything in your vest that can help us?
当然  我这有多功能工具
Oh, yeah. Heck, I got a guppie multi-tool,
太阳能手持电扇
I've got a solar-powered hand fan,
护目镜  内置指南针
got camo glasses, built-in compass,
蛇咬急救箱
Snake bite kit--
就是没有咯
So nothing?
才不是  我能生火
Well, not nothing. I can build a fire.
真棒
Oh, great.
你看  卡塞尔
You know what, Castle?
你举我一把我就能自己爬出去
I can pull myself out if you could boost me up.
那我怎么出去
Well, then how am I gonna get out?
我车里有绳子
I have a rope in the car.
我走回去拿
I was gonna hike back to get it.
你就把我一个人留在这里
You're gonna leave me here alone?
好吧  等一下
Okay, whoa. Just hold on a second.
我们退回来想一想
Let's just back up and think about this.
这坑怎么就在这儿呢
What is this pit doing out here in the first place?
有人或者是
Someone or...
有东西建了它
something had to build it.
"东西"  卡塞尔
"Something," Castle?
你觉得大脚怪自带铲子到这儿的
You think that bigfoot came out here with a shovel?
不  你没准是对的
No, you're probably right.
我觉得不是大脚怪建的
I don't think bigfoot built this.
没准是一些猎人或者是偷猎者挖的
Yeah, some hunters or poachers probably dug it up.
抓什么  你看看这坑的大小
Hunting what? Look at the size of this thing.
没准是逃犯为了防止人来才建的
Maybe our fugitive built it in case anyone came out here.
我还是觉得大脚怪的推理比较好
I'm more comfort with the idea of bigfoot building it.
行了  卡塞尔
Come on, Castle.
你先半蹲怎么样
Why don't you pop a squat?
-我们来个拉拉队的动作  -好吧
- We'll pull a cheerleader move. - Right.
你不是应该穿个超短裙吗
Shouldn't you be wearing a short skirt for this?
上吧
It's the move.
你知道  这个坑虽然有点粗糙
You know, though, this pit is kind of crudely built.
但是  有一些灵长类动物
And, uh, some primates have been known to...
喜欢在这种地方
make and...
老天  卡塞尔
Oh, jeez! Castle!
使用工具来诱捕猎物
use tools to trap prey.
你能别动吗  抓紧我
Would you stand still? Hold me.
使劲
Now.
我是说
Yeah, I'm just saying,
我可不想成为大脚怪的盘中餐
I don't want to end up as bigfoot dinner.
你知道吗  卡塞尔
You know, Castle,
现在真是一种报应呢
there is a bit of poetic justice in this.
怎么就是报应了
Poetic justice how?
我说你仔细想想
Well, I mean, think about it.
你给阿丽克西斯设了陷阱
You set a trap for Alexis,
现在有人
and now someone
或者有东西给你设了陷阱
or something has set one for you.
答应我你会回来
Promise me you'll come back.
以防我没及时回来
In case I don't make it.
真有意思啊
Oh, that's cute.
没开玩笑  快点回来
But seriously, hurry back!
好吗
'kay?
看什么呢
What's that?
没什么  你发现什么了
Nothing. What do you got?
拿上外套
Grab your coat.
有人发现科特·威尔森了
We got a hit on that photo of Kurt Wilson.
安的邻居刚看到他
One of Anne's neighbors just saw him
进入了她的公寓
go into her apartment.
威尔森  纽约警局
Hey, Wilson. NYPD.
逃跑的技术不怎么样啊  威尔森
Not much of a running back there, Wilson,
毕竟缺乏锻炼
But then, you're out of training.
好了  走吧
All right. Let's go.
我们抓到他了  他什么都不说
We got him, and he's not talking.
你想让我们怎么办
What do you want us to do?
好  查查他的衣服上有没有安的血迹
Okay, check his clothes for Anne's blood.
你们的犯罪现场找得怎么样
How you guys doing on the crime scene?
我们碰上了点意外
We ran into a little snag,
但是等我们找到了
but when we find it,
希望我们会找到证据
Hopefully we'll find evidence
将命案与科特·威尔森联系起来
that leads us straight to Kurt Wilson,
这样我们就不需要他说话了
and we won't need him to talk.
哦  小叉子
Heh. Ah, spork...
当初他们都取笑你
They all laughed at you.
贝克特
Beckett?
你终于回来了  怎么这么久
Thank god you are back. What took you so long?
好了  别闹  把我弄出去
Ha ha ha ha ha. Okay. Get me outta here now.
贝克特
Beckett?
凯特
Kate...
救命
Help!
拜托
Please...
别吃我
Don't eat me.
警察
Police!
转过身去
Turn around!
把手举起来
Put your hands up.
贝克特  你在做什么
Beckett, what are you doing?
你疯了吗  它听不懂你的话
Are you crazy? It can't understand you!
快
Now!
开枪
Whoa! Shoot it!
开枪啊  你在等什么
Shoot it! What are you waiting for?
我的背
Oh, my back!
它在说话
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's talking.
不
No!
别开枪  别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
别开枪
Don't shoot!
请别开枪
Please don't shoot.
别对他开枪
Don't shoot him.
太令人失望了
Well, this is a huge disappointment.
不  这是个天大的误会
No, this is a big misunderstanding.
是吗
Is it?
那爪子
'cause those claws
完全能够造成安脸上的伤
could've easily caused Anne's injuries.
什么  我决不会伤害安
What? I'd never hurt Anne.
你这身装扮出现在
Do you actually expect us to believe that
她被袭击的现场
with you dressed up in this... getup
还指望我们相信你的话吗
right in the same area where she was attacked?
等等  她是在这被袭击的吗
Wait. Sh-she was attacked here?
我以为是在城里
I-I-I thought she was attacked in the city.
不是
No.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
情况看来很糟
This looks bad.
让我尽量解释一下  好吗
Let me--let me just try and explain. Okay?
我知道安要独自来这儿
I knew that Anne was coming out here on her own,
我承认我跟踪了她
and--and I-I admit that I followed her.
为什么
Why?
因为我以为她发现了大脚怪
Because I think she found bigfoot.
或许是她发现了一个蠢货装扮成大脚怪
Or maybe she just found an idiot dressed up as bigfoot
然后把她杀了
who then killed her.
不  我没有伤害安
No! I didn't hurt Anne!
好吧  那你只是跟踪了她
Oh, okay. So you just stalked her?
我只是...
Look, I just...
我只是想  就这一次
I just wanted, just this once,
看看这传说中的野兽
to lay eyes on this elusive beast.
所以我设了这个陷阱
A-and that's why I built this man-trap
穿上了这散发麝香的衣服
and--and--and I'm in this suit, drenched in deer musk.
我就说有怪味嘛
Is that what that smell is?
这是引诱剂  引他们出来
It's an attractant. It--it lures them out.
很有效
A-and it's working, too.
一小时之前  我听到
I mean, a-about an hour ago, I-I heard--
我听到叫声和敲木头的声音
I heard vocalizations and--and knocking on wood.
那些是经典的大脚怪交配鸣叫
And--and those are--are classic bigfoot mating calls.
我还发现了些吃剩的食物和粪便
I also found some, uh, half-eaten food and some scat.
更不用说  大脚怪用来
And not to mention, a tool
重击猎物的工具
that bigfoot used to club his prey.
上面还有血迹
And there's blood on it.
等等  你看见了一只有血迹的棍棒
Wait a minute. You saw a bloody club?
是啊
Yeah.
带我们去你发现的地点
Show us where you found it.
你认识这个吗
Do you recognize this?
上面是安·卡蒂诺的血迹
That's Anne Cardinal's blood.
我们在检测你的衣服
We're checking your clothes for it, too,
还有上面的污迹  一定会证明你去过树林
along with the dirt that is gonna place you in the woods.
你们就跟其他那些警察一样
You're just like those other cops.
你们宁愿主观臆断也不去查真相
You'd rather make your case than see the truth.
真相是什么  科特
And what is the truth, Kurt?
我是住在那树林里
I was living out in those woods,
但是安并不是来捕猎我的
but Anne wasn't trying to hunt me down.
她是来帮助我
She came out there to help me,
给我带食物和日常用品
bring me food and supplies.
安为什么要帮助一个杀害了她室友的人
Why would Anne help the man that murdered her roommate?
几个月前
A few months ago,
我从藏身处跑出来找到安
I came out of hiding to find Anne.
我告诉她我是无辜的  我没有杀贾丝婷
I told her I was innocent, that I didn't kill Justine,
我求她去查查这案子
and I begged her to look into the case.
她答应了  因为她相信我
And she agreed to because she believed me.
好吧  我有点更怀疑了
Yeah, well, I'm a little more skeptical.
这我可以担保
I can vouch for that.
你有暴力史  科特
You have a history of violence, Kurt.
很显然贾丝婷辍学
And it's pretty clear that Justine dropped out
想跟你分手  所以你杀了她
and tried to break up with you, so you killed her.
贾丝婷辍学不是为了摆脱我
Justine did not drop out to get away from me.
我们爱着对方
She and I were in love.
当她告诉我她要离开哈德逊大学
When she told me she was quitting Hudson,
我也决定一起走
I decided to go, too.
我们俩计划转到别的学校
The two of us were planning on transferring to another school.
她死前一周  我们甚至
We'd even toured the campus
还去了宾汉姆顿的纽约州大学参观
at S.U.N.Y. Binghamton the week before.
我确定他们留有记录
And I'm sure they have a record of that somewhere.
如果你不是贾丝婷离开哈德逊大学的原因
If you weren't the reason why Justine left Hudson,
那原因是什么
then what was?
她从没告诉我
She never told me.
她只说事情进展不顺利
She just said that things weren't working out.
但现在我花了很多时间
But now I've spent a lot of time
思考过这件事
thinking about that,
唯一说得通的理由
and the only thing that makes sense
就是有一个她害怕的人存在
is if there was someone there that she was afraid of.
比如谁
Like who?
同学  教授  我不知道
A classmate, a professor-- I don't know.
但我想安查出了真相
But I think Anne found out.
上周我去她工作的地方见她
Last week when I came to see her at her work,
她说她就快有答案了
she said that she was close to having answers.
接着我就得知她死了
And the next thing I know, she's dead.
所以我想无论是谁干的  也是杀贾丝婷的凶手
So I figure whoever did it killed Justine, too.
所以我才闯入她的公寓
And that--that's why I broke into her apartment.
我在找...  我也不知道
I was looking for... I don't know,
线索也好  答案也罢
Clues, answers, a-anything.
你认为杀害了安和贾丝婷的人
The person that you think killed Anne and Justine--
你想得出是谁吗
Do you have any idea who it is?
一定得是
It had to be someone
能说服贾丝婷开门的人
who could talk Justine into opening her door.
是她认识的人
You know, someone she knew.
所以他们才会想要偷她的项链
It's the only reason that they would steal her necklace.
那根本不值钱
It wasn't worth anything.
你不会是指一个青石坠子吧
You wouldn't be referring to a lapis pendant, would you?
贾丝婷从没摘下来过
Justine never took it off.
而我发现她时  那坠子不见了
When I found her, that pendant was gone.
拿走它的人  杀害了她
Whoever took it killed her.
科特
Kurt...
这是贾丝婷的坠子吗
Is this Justine's pendant?
所以安才吞了它
That's why Anne had it.
这坠子是证据  她找到了真正的凶手
The pendant is proof. She found the real killer.
凶手最近跟她接触过
It has to be someone she spent time with recently.
一个走进她生活的人
Someone she got close to.
戴文教授
Professor Devlin.
有什么需要我帮忙的吗  探长
Can I help you, detective?
事实上  还真有
As a matter of fact, you can.
关于贾丝婷·伯顿你知道些什么
What can you tell us about Justine Bolton?
她是哈德逊大学的学生
Uh, she was a student at Hudson
不幸去世了
who died rather tragically.
你知道的不止这一点吧
Well, you knew her as more than that.
她在大一的时候选修过
She took your introduction to anthropology course
你的人类学概论课
her freshman year.
的确  所以对于她的离世我感到很悲痛
Yes, she did, which made her loss a personal one.
但是我不知道
But I fail to see what that--
你知道在她上完课后
Were you aware that after she took that course,
她告诉辅导员说她很害怕吗
she told her counselor that she was afraid
因为学校里的某个人
because someone on campus--
她没说是谁
she never said who...
不过那个人对她很痴迷
but someone was obsessed with her?
她肯定是说她男朋友吧
Well, no doubt she was talking about her boyfriend--
那个杀害她的人
the young man who killed her.
但她见辅导员的时候
Ah, but she took the meeting with her counselor
还不认识她男朋友
before she met her boyfriend.
却认识你
But she had met you.
你的执教生涯很离奇啊  教授
You've had an odd career, professor.
六年之内辗转四所学校当老师
You taught at four schools in six years.
所以我打听了一下  他们都明里暗里地说到
So I made a few inquiries, and there were intimations
你有跟踪和性骚扰的行为
of stalking, sexual harassment,
还有更过分的举动
and even worse.
这些都是谣传
All of which were false.
请允许我说明
And let me point out,
我从来没有被投诉过
no action was ever taken against me.
贾丝婷在被杀害的那天
Justine had scheduled a meeting with the dean
本来安排了和系主任的面谈
on the day that she was killed
解释她为什么要退学
to explain why she was leaving.
你不能让她和系主任见面
You couldn't let her take that meeting.
因为如果她去了
If she did...
你那些肮脏的过往就要被揭发了
your dirty history would be exposed.
你就完蛋了
You'd be finished.
所以你杀了她
So you killed her.
作为"掠食者"
And being the predator that you are,
你把她的吊坠拿走当做纪念品
you took a souvenir-- her pendant.
当大家都认为科特·威尔森是嫌疑犯的时候
With all the suspicion on Kurt Wilson,
没人在关注你
no one was looking at you.
直到安的出现
Until Anne came along.
我不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
安发现了那个吊坠
Anne found that pendant.
她知道凶手是你
She knew it was you.
当她走进森林的时候  你跟踪了她
And when she went into the woods, you followed her.
什么森林  我没去过森林
What woods? I wasn't in any woods.
我们查过你的通话记录
We checked your phone records.
当安被袭击的时候
Your cell pinged the same tower as Anne's did
你和她的手机信号都来自一个信号塔
around the time that she was attacked.
这证明了你在案发现场
That places you at the crime scene.
我们也找到了一根带有安血液的棍子
We also found a club with Anne's blood on it
那上面还有另外一个人的DNA
and someone else's D.N.A.
根据你现在看我的表情
And based on the look that you're giving me right now,
我十分肯定那就是你的DNA
I'm pretty damn sure it's yours.
卡塞尔
So, Castle,
大脚怪并不存在  你失望吗
are you disappointed that there's no bigfoot after all?
我不确定它真的不存在
Well, I'm not so sure there isn't.
我觉得也许他就在某个地方
I'm thinking maybe he's out there somewhere,
如果是这样的话  希望我能见一见他
and if he is, I hope to see him one day.
当然最好是远远的看
Preferably from a safe distance.
谢谢你们  完成安未完成的事
Thank you... for finishing what Anne started.
因为你们的努力
Because of you guys,
杀害贾丝婷的凶手不再逍遥法外
Justine's killer will pay for what he did to her,
我也洗刷了罪名
and, uh, I'm a free man.
那你接下来想干什么
So what's next for you?
我要继续做安的研究
I'm going to continue Anne's work.
你要调查大脚怪  为什么啊
You're gonna research bigfoot, why?
当她建议我躲在森林里的时候
Well, when she suggested I hide out in those woods,
她说我会有伴儿的
she told me I'd have company out there.
她说得没错
She was right.
你听到了没
Did you hear that?
我要去拿我的装备了
I gotta go and get my outfit.
嗨
Hey.
你的...还有点...
You, um... you still got a little... on your...
真的很抱歉
I'm--I'm so sorry about that.
你知道那有多丢人啊
Do you know how humiliating that was?
我发誓  我真的不知道是你
I swear, I had no idea it was you.
不过  阿丽克西斯  你为什么要偷食物
But, Alexis, why were you stealing food?
因为我没钱了
Because I ran out of money.
你怎么会把钱都花光呢  除非
How could you have possibly spent all your money unless--
等一下  不会吧  你是不是
Wait. No. Are you...
你是不是有什么麻烦
Are--are you in some kind of trouble?
我没把钱花光  我只是捐出去了
No, I didn't spend it. I gave it away.
是投资  真的
Invested it, really.
投资什么
Invested in what?
我朋友乔纳举办了一场集资活动
My friend Jonah at school has a crowdfunding campaign
他准备在摩天大楼的屋顶上种竹子
to plant bamboo forests on the roof of skyscrapers
这可以净化空气
to help clean the air.
你为什么不直接告诉我呢
Well, why didn't you just come to me?
因为我不想听你的老生常谈了
Because I didn't want the speech.
我没有  什么老生常谈
I don't--what speech?
我们这种有钱人
That people like us need to be careful
应该小心谨慎
with the kind of money we have.
别人可能会占我们的便宜
People might try to take advantage.
这个啊
Oh, that speech. Yeah.
爸爸  你相信那些不可思议的事情
Dad, you believe in all these unbelievable things,
比如说大脚怪  我从来没有说过什么
like bigfoot, and I don't judge.
但是  我相信人和他们能做到的事情
But... I believe in people and what they can accomplish.
我相信乔纳和他的远见
I believe in Jonah and his vision,
我想支持他
and I wanted to support him.
我认为他能改变世界
I think he could make a real difference in the world.
好吧  也许把我所有的零花钱都给他
And, okay, so maybe it was stupid
是一件很蠢的事
to give him all of my allowance,
但我可不是第一个为了坚信的事
But I am not the first person to do something stupid
去做蠢事的人
for something they believe in.
对对  你不是第一个
No. No, you're not.
事实上  我们的家风就是如此
Matter of fact, it's a... bit of a family trait.
但是  你还是欠我
But... you do owe me
一顿烤牛排
a chateaubriand.
咱们去马戏团餐厅吧
So... let's go to Le Cirque.
然后  叫乔纳这小子和我们一起吧
And then, uh, call this Jonah guy, have him meet us.
我想听听他要怎么改变世界
I'd like to hear about how he's gonna change the world.
真的吗
Really?
我也相信人
I believe in people, too.
和借钱的人
And borrowers.
还有大脚怪
And bigfoot.